Finding Aid for Carl Cohen papers, 1950-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical and Name files
  - Medical Ethics: lectures, notes, writings
    - Death
      - When are Means for the Support of Life Extraordinary? 1985 (Box 48)
    - Diagnosis-Related Groups (DRG), 2 folders (Box 48)
    - DNA, 4 folders (Box 48)
    - Do not resuscitate
      - Determining Whom to Resuscitate, 1986 (Box 48)
      - Do Not Resuscitate Orders in the Operating Room 1990 (Box 48)
    - Doctors and lawyers (Box 48)
    - Drugs (On the Ethical Use of Drugs), 1994 (Box 48)
    - Duty to warn (Box 48)
    - Ethics
      - Ethical Analysis in Medicine (Box 48)
      - Ethical Issues in the Future of Medicine 1987 (Box 48)
      - Ethics, Overview (School of Dentistry lecture) 1988 (Box 48)
    - Fetal rights (When Interests of the Fetus and the Mother Conflict) (Box 48)
    - Fraud 1988 (Box 48)
    - Genetic research (When Should Genetic Research be Stopped?), 1993 (Box 48)
    - Health care
      - Is There a Right to Health Care?, 1992 (Box 48)
      - Moral Issues in Health Care Delivery (Box 48)
    - Health and disease (Box 48)
    - Health reform, Oregon style, 1993 (Box 48)
    - Human experimentation
      - Children (Box 49)
      - Department of Health and Human Services (Box 49)
      - General, 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Regents letter (Box 49)
    - Law (Medical Ethics and the Law) (Box 49)
    - Medical education (Ethics in Medical Education) (Box 49)
    - Memorial Advisory & Planning Service 1989 (Box 49)
    - Mental health (Should Mental Health Care be Rationed?) (Box 49)
    - Neurology (Box 49)
    - Non-compliant patients (Box 49)
    - Nutritional support (Ethical Issues in Nutritional Support) (Box 49)
    - Oncology ethics (Box 49)
    - Organ Donations
      - Donated Organs as a National Resource (Box 49)
      - Moral Issues Roused by Organ Transplantation (Box 49)
      - Rationing Health Care--and What can be Learned from Organ Transplantation 1992 (Box 49)
      - Transplantation Ethical Issues: A Framework for Analysis (Box 49)
      - What Transplantation Can Teach Us About Health Care Reform ` (Box 49)
    - Pain (Box 49)
    - Patients (What is a Patient?) (Box 49)
    - Philosophical Issues in Medicine lectures, flyers, 67 folders (Box 49)
    - Philosophy in clinical practice 1985 (Box 49)
    - Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 1985 (Box 49)
    - Pre-Med interviews, discussing tough questions (Box 49)
    - Professionals
      - Must the Ethical Standpoints be Impartial? (Box 49)
      - Professionals in Business: Conflict and Resolution, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Program in Human Values in Medicine description 1986 (Box 49)
    - Psychiatry (Ethical Controversies in Medicine and Psychiatry), 1990 (Box 49)
    - Quality of Life
      - On the Quality of Life: Some Philosophical Reflections, 1982 (Box 49)
      - Quality of Life and Coronary Artery Bypass Surgery: Some Philosophical Reflections (Box 49)
    - Reproductive technologies (New Reproductive Technologies--Moral Issues) (Box 49)
    - Right to die
      - Ethical Issues in Withdrawal of Life Support, 1991 (Box 49)
      - Introductions (Box 49)
      - Killing and Letting Die (Box 49)
      - Nancy Cruzan's Right to Die and the Supreme Court, 1990 (Box 49)
      - Newborns (Box 49)
      - Terminal care, 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Update 1987 (Box 49)
    - Scientific uncertainties (Philosophical Reflections about Scientific Uncertainties: Choosing Among the Options for the Treatment of Prostate Cancer) (Box 49)
    - Secret research (Box 49)
    - Sex
      - Ethical Issues in Selecting the Sex of a Child 1992 (Box 49)
      - Sex, Birth Control and Human Life, 1986 (Box 49)
      - Sex and Censorship 1990 (Box 49)
    - Suicide (Box 49)
    - Surgeons (Some Philosophical Puzzles, Surgeon-Patient Environment), 1979 (Box 49)
    - Technology (Technology and Decision Making in Medicine) (Box 49)
    - Thank you notes (Box 49)
  - Subjects 1963-1988
    - Aiken (NY review) (Box 50)
    - American Association of University Professors (Box 50)
    - American Jewish Committee
      - Israel notes (Box 50)
      - Annual meeting (Box 50)
      - General (Box 50)
    - American Nuclear Society (Box 50)
    - American Philosophical Association (Program committee) 1977, 3 folders (Box 50)
    - American Society for Political and Legal Philosophy (NOMOS)
      - Papers (Box 50)
      - Program committee (Box 50)
      - Sosa, Ernest (Box 50)
      - Correspondence (Box 50)
      - Barber, Benjamin (Box 50)
      - Bedau, Hugo (Box 50)
      - Bolling, Richard (Box 50)
      - Braybrooke, David (Box 50)
      - Dahl, Robert (Box 50)
      - Kateb, George (Box 50)
      - McKay, Robert (Box 50)
      - Railton, Peter (Box 50)
      - Silber, John (Box 50)
      - Van Alstyne, William (Box 50)
    - AMOCO award (Box 50)
    - Arboretum disorder 1985 (Box 50)
    - Arts and Crafts, 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Autonomy and government (Box 50)
    - Benzinger Library (Box 50)
    - Bergmann, Frithjof/Goodman, Frederick (faculty awards) (Box 50)
    - Beth Israel
      - General (Box 50)
      - Correspondence (Box 50)
      - January membership meeting 1979 (Box 50)
      - 2010 Washtenaw (Box 50)
      - Ann Arbor News, letter June 1979 (Box 50)
      - Ha Shaliaih (newsletter) (Box 50)
      - Groundbreaking (Box 50)
      - Dedication (Box 50)
    - Big Ten Athletic Conference Faculty Representative 1978 (Box 50)
    - Boca Raton (Box 50)
    - Bunzel, John (Box 50)
    - Burks, Arthur (re: Klingensmith paper) (Box 50)
    - California, University of, San Diego (Richard Popkin) (Box 50)
    - Central Michigan University (Box 50)
    - CIVS (Collegiate Institute for Values and Science), 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Civil Liberties Board, 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Collier Books (Paul Edwards) (Box 50)
    - Columbia letter (Box 50)
    - Columbia University Press, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Communism, Fascism, Democracy (2 folders (Box 51)
    - Coronary Artery Bypass Surgery (CABS) 1981 (Box 51)
    - Conscientious Objection 1968 (Box 51)
    - CRASS (Committee of Recent Alumni, Students and Staff/Comrades Raging Against Student Somnolence) 1974 (Box 51)
    - Davidson College 1980-1981
      - General (Box 51)
      - Reynolds lectureship (Box 51)
      - Bakke (Box 51)
      - 1980 (Box 51)
      - Clippings and other materials (Box 51)
      - Directory (Box 51)
      - Letters of notice (?) (Box 51)
      - Syllabi, 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Exams, 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Speech paper (Box 51)
      - Bliss, Frank (Box 51)
      - Residential College (Box 51)
      - Maydale (Box 51)
      - MacCormac, Earl (Box 51)
      - Stell, Lance (Box 51)
      - Zimmerman, T. C. Price (Box 51)
      - 1981 (Box 51)
      - Staff benefits (Box 51)
    - Dearborn misc. 1965-1966 (Box 51)
    - Dushkin, David -- Democracy 1963-1967 (Box 51)
    - Economic status of the faculty 1964-1965 (Box 51)
    - Educational Testing Service 1971 (Box 51)
    - Eleusis 1980 (Box 51)
    - Faculty counselors for freshmen and sophomores 1962 (Box 51)
    - FBI 1976 (Box 51)
    - Fleming remarks 1978 (Box 51)
    - Genetic Engineering Consortium 1981 (Box 51)
    - Georgia, University of, Press (Box 51)
    - Graduate Requirement Committee, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Graduate students (Box 51)
    - Grant #800 (Box 51)
    - Grolier's (Box 51)
    - Henley gift (Box 51)
    - Hospital letters (Box 51)
    - Houston (Box 51)
    - Humanities, National Foundation on the Arts and the (Box 51)
    - Ideals of Freedom, Washington D.C. 1962 (Box 51)
    - Illinois (Box 51)
    - Iowa medical conference 1981 (Box 51)
    - Journalism seminar (Box 51)
    - Kalamazoo College (Box 51)
    - Kalamazoo October 1976 (Box 51)
    - Literature, Science, and the Arts
      - Nelvia Van't Hul 1981 (Box 51)
      - Blue Ribbon Commission 1984 (Box 51)
    - MacMillan Company (Box 52)
    - Marquette March 1975 (Box 52)
    - Medical experimentation, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Michigan Daily (Box 52)
    - Merit scholarships (Box 52)
    - Military in the University (Box 52)
    - Nation (Publication) (Box 52)
    - Nazis (Box 52)
    - NEH Seminar for Journalists 1970s
      - Correspondents
        - Bedau, Hugo (Box 52)
        - Cranberg, Gilbert (Box 52)
        - Dorsen, Norman (Box 52)
        - Fader, Daniel (Box 52)
        - Fleming, Robben (Box 52)
        - Freedman, Monroe (Box 52)
        - Green, Robert (Box 52)
        - Haiman, Franklyn (Box 52)
        - Kipnis, Kenneth, 2 folders (Box 52)
        - Markovic, Mihailo (Box 52)
        - Neier, A. J. (Box 52)
        - Searle, John (Box 52)
        - Stich, Steve (Box 52)
        - Van Alstyne, William (Box 52)
        - van den Haag, Ernest (Box 52)
        - Wellman, Carl (Box 52)
      - Seminar
        - Fellows 1976-1977 (Box 52)
        - Schedule (Box 52)
        - Seminar 1977 (Box 52)
        - Sketch 1978 (Box 52)
    - National Institute of Health (NIH) (Box 52)
    - National Humanities Center, 7 folders (Box 52)
    - Nuclear free Ann Arbor (Box 52)
    - Nuclear free zone (Box 52)
    - Peace studies (Box 52)
    - Peru -- final reports (Box 52)
    - Problems of Communism (publication) (Box 52)
    - Rackham grant (Box 52)
    - Rice, Warner (award) (Box 52)
    - Santa Barbara (Box 52)
    - Society for the Philosophical Study of Dialectical Materialism (Box 52)
    - Soviet-American dialogue (Box 52)
    - Study abroad (Box 52)
    - Summer fellowship (Box 52)
    - Teach-in, Vietnam, Ann Arbor September 1965 (Box 52)
    - Toledo (Box 52)
    - Trends (Box 52)
    - United Fund 1967-1989 (Box 52)
    - University of Michigan
      - Commencements 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Program in Ethics and Humanism in Medicine (Box 52)
    - University of Michigan Press (Democracy) (Box 52)
    - Wallenberg, Raoul (Box 52)
    - Warner Lambert (Box 52)
    - Washington 1965 (Box 52)
    - WJIM (Box 52)
    - Yugoslavian philosopher 1972 (Box 52)
  - People file 1963-1988
    - Alston, William (Box 53)
    - Avineri, Shlomo (Box 53)
    - Bauer, Yehuda (Box 53)
    - Bedau, Hugo (Box 53)
    - Bolling, Richard (Box 53)
    - Bookbinder, Hyman (American Jewish Committee) (Box 53)
    - Braybrooke, David (Box 53)
    - Brown, Paul (Regent) (Box 53)
    - Burks, David (Box 53)
    - Butts, Thomas (Box 53)
    - Cahn, Steve (Box 53)
    - Caplan, Art (Columbia Medical School) (Box 53)
    - Carduner, Sylvia (Box 53)
    - Copi, Irving, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Cullen, J. (Box 53)
    - Davis, Michael (Box 53)
    - Feingold, Eugene (Box 53)
    - Ferran, Peter (Box 53)
    - Flynn, J. R. (Box 53)
    - Frye, Billy, 16 folders (Box 53)
    - Galler, Bernard (Box 53)
    - Gamson, Zelda (Box 53)
    - Gould, Jim (Box 53)
    - Greenawalt (Box 53)
    - Haithcox, John P. (Box 53)
    - Hannaford, Robert V. (Box 53)
    - Hart, Senator Philip A. (Box 53)
    - Hedman, Carl (Box 53)
    - Heyns, Roger W. (Box 53)
    - Hoerster, Norbert (Box 53)
    - Hornback, Bert (Box 53)
    - Howe, Leroy (Box 53)
    - Kaplan, Abe (Box 53)
    - Knott, John (Box 53)
    - Kornblum, Sylvan (Box 53)
    - Kripke, Ned (Box 53)
    - Larimore, Ann (Box 53)
    - Lehman, Fritz (Box 53)
    - Lipscomb, Jim, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Livermore, Shaw (Box 53)
    - Makedon, Alex (Box 53)
    - Marshall, S. L. A. (WWJ TV re: ROTC) (Box 53)
    - Mathews, Bill (Box 53)
    - Mersereau, John (Box 53)
    - Miro Quesada, Francisco (Box 53)
    - Mendenhall, George (Box 53)
    - McIntyre, Steve (Box 53)
    - Minas, J. S. (Box 53)
    - Mitgang, Lee (Box 53)
    - Morley, George (Box 53)
    - Moya-Raggio, Eliana (Box 53)
      see Carduner, Sylvia
    - Murphy, Irene (Box 53)
    - Nordby, Virginia (Box 53)
    - Norris, Margot (Box 53)
    - Pahlabod, Shahyar (Box 53)
    - Prosterman, H. Scott (Box 53)
    - Rodcliffe, Mark (Box 53)
    - Reynolds, William Bradford (Attorney General), 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Rhodes, Frank H. T. (Box 53)
    - Robertson, Jim, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Ross, Marc, 4 folders (Box 53)
    - Rosthal, Robert (Box 53)
    - Russell, Trusten (Conference Board of Associated Research Councils) (Box 53)
    - Sax, Joseph (Box 53)
    - Sayles, Edward (Box 53)
    - Schipper, Edith, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Schoeman, Ferdinand, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Schrag, Francis (Box 53)
    - Shapiro, Harold (Box 53)
    - Siegler, Fred (Box 53)
    - Simon, Myron (Box 53)
    - Steiner, Peter, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Stell, Lance, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Stevenson, Charles (Box 53)
    - Stich, Steve, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Sussman, Alfred (Box 53)
    - Thuma, Burton (Box 53)
    - Umama, John (Box 53)
    - Vernon, Tom (Box 53)
    - Walsh, Martin (Box 53)
    - Weisinger, Herbert (Box 53)
    - Wellman, Carl (Box 53)
    - Wheatley, Jon (Box 53)
    - White, Nick (Philosophy courses) (Box 53)
    - Whitman, Merrill Jay (Box 53)
    - Will, Fred (Box 53)
    - Wright, Quincy (Box 53)
    - Yamamoto, Yutaka (Box 53)
    - Zarafonetis, Chris (Box 53)
    - Zerby, Lewis, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Zorn, Jens (Box 53)
  - Combined People and Subject File 1988-2001
    - Activity report (Cohen/Shope) 1988 (Box 54)
    - Activity sheet (Residential College) 1989-1993 (Box 54)
    - Advance (Box 54)
    - Alcoholics (New England Journal of Medicine) (Box 54)
    - Animals, 9 folders (Box 54)
    - August, David (Box 54)
    - Barkan, Ariel (Box 54)
    - Bekoff, Marc (Box 54)
    - Bennett, William, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Beth Israel, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Blanchard, James (Box 54)
    - Bole, Giles (Box 54)
    - Bollinger, Lee (Box 54)
    - Brockman, John (Box 54)
    - Brown, Paul (Box 54)
    - Budnitz, Liz (Box 54)
    - Bull, Frank (Box 54)
    - Butcher, Phil (McGraw Hill) (Box 54)
    - Byrne, Robert (Chess) (Box 54)
    - Capital punishment (Box 54)
    - Castration (Barkan) (Box 54)
    - Charfoos & Christensen (Box 54)
    - Chronicles of Higher Education, 8 folders (Box 54)
    - Clippings, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Racial discrimination report (?) (Box 54)
    - Commentary (publication), 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Conference on Ethics and Humanism in Medicine (CEHM) (Box 54)
    - Colao, Tony (agent) (Box 54)
    - Cutler, Richard (Box 54)
    - Curriculum/Davis/blueprints (Box 54)
    - Curriculum improvements (Box 54)
    - Davis, Wayne (Box 54)
    - Davidson College (Box 54)
    - Democracy (book) (Box 54)
    - Democracy in workplace (correspondence with Garten) 1992 (Box 54)
    - Discriminatory harassment policy, UM 1993, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Darwall, Steve 1997 (Box 54)
    - Detroit News, 5 folders (Box 54)
    - Drongowski, Robert (see Francione, Gary) (Box 54)
    - Duderstadt, James (Box 54)
    - Eagle, Herb, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - East Tennessee State University debate on animal research 1991 (Box 54)
    - Emerson School 1997-1998 (Box 54)
    - Ethicists (Box 54)
    - Ethics (Box 54)
    - Feinberg, Joel (Box 54)
    - Fett, James (Box 54)
    - Fine, Gail (Box 54)
    - Fink, Jon (Box 54)
    - Fish, Stanley 1996 (Box 54)
    - Fitzgerald, Tom (Box 54)
    - Foote, Edward (Box 54)
    - Ford Auditorium (Box 54)
    - Ford, Charles (Box 54)
    - Francione, Gary/Drongowski, Robert (Box 54)
    - Frank, Barney (Box 54)
    - FOIA, 5 folders (Box 54)
    - Frier, Bruce (Box 54)
    - Frum, David (Box 54)
    - Frye, Billy 1995 (Box 54)
    - Geller, Brad/Goldman, Edward (Box 54)
    - Genome Ethics Committee, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Georgia Press (Box 54)
    - Germline genetic technology (Box 54)
    - Gilbert, Joseph (logic) (Box 54)
    - Giles, Thomas/Kesler, Rebecca (Box 54)
    - Giraldo, Z. I. (affirmative action) (Box 54)
    - Goals of medicine (Box 54)
    - Goldberg, David, 12 folders (Box 54)
    - Goldman, Edward (see Geller, Brad) (Box 54)
    - Goold, Susan (Box 54)
    - Greenhaven Press (Box 54)
    - Greenhills School (Box 54)
    - Greenwood Publishing Group (Box 54)
    - Grochowski, Eugene (Box 54)
    - Gross, Barry (Box 54)
    - Harrison, Walter/Schultz, Robert (Box 55)
    - Hartford, Maureen (statement of student rights and responsibilities) (Box 55)
    - Harvard (Box 55)
    - Hastings, Henry 1991 (Box 55)
    - Holland, Elzora (Box 55)
    - Hopwood responses, UM (Box 55)
    - Howell, Joel/LaPuma, John, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Human Values in Medicine fund, 5 folders (Box 55)
    - Humane Society (Box 55)
    - Immuno (Box 55)
    - Jondahl, Lynn (Box 55)
    - Journal of Blacks in Higher Education (Box 55)
    - Kaplan, Abraham (Box 55)
    - Kesler, Rebecca (see Giles, Thomas) (Box 55)
    - Kopple, Barbara (filmmaker) (Box 55)
    - Kozodoy, Neal, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Lansing (Subcommittee on affirmative action) (Box 55)
    - LaPuma, John (see Howell, Joel) (Box 55)
    - Lectures (Box 55)
    - Lemos, Ramon (Box 55)
    - Levack, Erica, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Lichter, Paul (Box 55)
    - Maines, Ron (Box 55)
    - Medical Speakers Association, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Merit scholarship 1992 (Box 55)
    - Michigan Civil Rights Initiative (Box 55)
    - Michigan Medical Society 1989 (Box 55)
    - Michigan Quarterly Review 1993 (Box 55)
    - Miller, Jonathan (Box 55)
    - Murray, Charles (Box 55)
    - Musser, Amelia (Box 55)
    - NAACP (Box 55)
    - Naked racial preference, 6 folders (Box 55)
    - National Association of Scholars (Box 55)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Box 55)
    - Nazis (Box 55)
    - New York Times (letters to the editor)
      - Miscellaneous and general, 3 folders (Box 55)
      - Affirmative action, 8 folders (Box 55)
      - Anencephalic infant (Box 55)
      - Animal testing, 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Arithmetic (Box 55)
      - Bison story 1998 (Box 55)
      - Brain dead (Box 55)
      - Death penalty, 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Feminism (Box 55)
      - IQ (Box 55)
      - Morris chair (Box 55)
      - Nurses (Box 55)
      - Parody (Box 55)
      - Patient autonomy (Box 55)
      - Pronoun usage (Box 55)
      - Racial classification, University of California (Box 55)
      - Racial preference (Box 55)
      - Speaker choice (Box 55)
    - New Yorker (Box 55)
    - Nursing update (Box 55)
    - Nursing (surgical nurses) (Box 55)
    - Oregon State Senate (Box 55)
    - Osgood case, Carl Cohen affidavit 1995 (Box 55)
    - Pek, Sumer (Box 55)
    - Phi Chi notes, 3 folders (Box 55)
    - Phifer, Ken (Box 55)
    - Political correctness (Box 55)
    - Pollack, Lana (Box 55)
    - Power, Philip, 5 folders (Box 55)
    - Pugh, Deborah (Box 55)
    - Regents bylaw change (Box 55)
    - Rembrandt (Box 55)
    - Rhodes, Frank (Box 55)
    - Riesman, David (Box 55)
    - Ringler, Dan (Box 55)
    - Ross, Sherwood (Box 55)
    - Rowman & Littlefield Publishers (Box 55)
    - SACUA (Box 55)
    - Safire, William (Box 55)
    - Samp, Richard (Washington Legal Foundation) (Box 55)
    - Sandalow, Terry, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Schipper, Edith, 3 folders (Box 55)
    - Schlain, Jan, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Schultz, Robert (Box 55)
      (see Harrison, Walter)
    - Schwartz, Milton 1993 (Box 55)
    - Scripps Memorial Hospital 1997 (Box 55)
    - Seidler, Ingo, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Shapiro, Harold (Box 55)
    - Sharon, Zachary 1996 (Box 55)
    - Shevrin, Howard 1997 (Box 55)
    - Shope, Tom, 3 folders (Box 55)
    - Silverman, Stefanie (Box 55)
    - Simone, Cynthia (Box 55)
    - Sisson, Jim, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Social Philosophy and Policy Center (Box 55)
    - Stanley, Julian (Box 55)
    - SUNY (Box 55)
    - Stell, Lance 1994 (Box 55)
    - Swan song (Box 55)
    - Taheri, Paul (Ethics Committee) (Box 56)
    - Talks, past (Box 56)
    - Teaching award 1988 (Box 56)
    - Tell, David (Weekly Standard) (Box 56)
    - Tenure committee 1988 (Box 56)
    - Tobacco (TIAA-CREF) (Box 56)
    - Transition (Box 56)
    - Transplant and Health Policy Center (Box 56)
    - Tufts 1996 (Box 56)
    - Umbrella Committee (Box 56)
    - University of Michigan alumni, 7 folders (Box 56)
    - University of Michigan policies on discrimination and discriminatory harassment 1988-1995 (Box 56)
    - University of Michigan policy on sexual orientation 1990-1991 (Box 56)
    - Velazco y Trianosky, Gregory (Box 56)
    - Vernon, Tom (Box 56)
    - Voorhees, John (cyclosporine) (Box 56)
    - Wall Street Journal (Box 56)
    - Warner Lambert-Parke Davis (Box 56)
    - Weg, John (faculty merit tuition scholarship fund) (Box 56)
    - Weekly Standard (Box 56)
    - Weiner, Gary (Box 56)
    - Weinreich, Gabriel (Box 56)
    - Weisskopf, Tom (Box 56)
    - Wenley, Robert Mark (Box 56)
    - Western Ontario, University of (Box 56)
    - White, Casey (Box 56)
    - White, Jim (Box 56)
    - White, Joseph (UM Business School) (Box 56)
    - Wiarda, Howard (Box 56)
    - Will, George (Box 56)
    - Wilson, Ted (Box 56)
    - Wooliscroft, James, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Yakin, Seth (Box 56)
    - Yamada, Tadataka (Box 56)
    - Yellow and blue (Box 56)
    - Zelnick, Bob (Box 56)
    - Zuidema, George, 2 folders (Box 56)
  - Program in Human Values in Medicine 1985-1996
    (Includes some earlier dated files; see also Medical Ethics topical files, boxes 48-49)
    - Admissions 1988 (Box 57)
    - Admissions, LS&A 1987 (Box 57)
    - Advisory Committee 1984 (Box 57)
    - Air Medical Transport conference 1994 (Box 57)
    - Alcoholics and liver transplantation 1989 (Box 57)
    - Alford, James A. 1985 (Box 57)
    - Alumni, "Morals, money, and medicine," 1992 (Box 57)
    - American Association for Laboratory Animal Science 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - American Cancer Society 1986 (Box 57)
    - American Medical Student Association 1985 (Box 57)
    - American Society of Anesthesiologists 1990 (Box 57)
    - American Veterinary Medical Association 1994 (Box 57)
    - Animal care committee 1985, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Animals
      - Dept. of Agriculture 1990 (Box 57)
      - New England Journal of Medicine 1986 (Box 57)
      - University of Michigan use form (Box 57)
    - Ann Arbor Association for Responsible Animal Treatment 1988, 3 folders (Box 57)
    - Archives of Internal Medicine 1985 (Box 57)
    - Assisted suicide 1995 (Box 57)
    - Association of American Medical Colleges 1985, 1992, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Barr, Duncan 1988 (Box 57)
    - Battle Creek Health System 1990 (Box 57)
    - Baumgarten, Elias 1986 (Box 57)
    - Benjamin, Martin 1988-1992, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Billi, Jack 1993 (Box 57)
    - Biomedical Communications 1987 (Box 57)
    - Birdsall, Ted 1986 (classified research) (Box 57)
    - Bishop, Ron 1989 (Box 57)
    - Borland, Karen 1991 (Box 57)
    - Borwein, Bessie 1995 (Box 57)
    - Bowerman, Cathy 1989 (Box 57)
    - Brewer, George 1989 (Box 57)
    - Brody, Howard 1986 (Box 57)
    - Brody, Jane 1987-1990, 3 folders (Box 57)
    - Bullard, Perry 1986, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Burt, Robert 1990, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Canadian Association of Transplantation 1994 (Box 57)
    - Caplan, Art 1988, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Career Planning & Placement 1990 (Box 57)
    - Catherine McAuley Health Center 1980, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Catlin, Jamie 1988 (Box 57)
    - Chandy, John 1986 (Box 57)
    - Chemical Engineering talk 1985 (Box 57)
    - Clark, Andrew (Box 57)
    - Classified Research 1986, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Cohen, Bennett 1988 (Box 57)
    - Cohen, Carl (Free Press) 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Coldwater Community Health Center 1990 (Box 57)
    - Collegiate Institute for Values and Science, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Collins, Francis 1992 (Box 57)
    - Committee for Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) 1984 (Box 57)
    - Comninou, Maria, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Component Directors (Ethics in the Medical curriculum) 1991 (Box 57)
    - Conference on Ethics, Humanism and Medicine
      - 1980, 3 folders (Box 57)